# **Chien-shih Huang**

## Research summary

Aims—to investigate the antecedents and consequences of governmental responsiveness to environmental issues at the subnational level.

Methods—Social network analysis, computational social sciences, survey experiments & experimental design, spatial econometrics.

Teaching— Intro to public administration and management, organizational behavior, behavioral public administration, policy process & theory, environmental governance, state and local government, research design, and quantitative methods.

	Academic Appointments
2022 —	Assistant Professor Graduate Institute of National Development, National Taiwan University, Taiwan
2021	Postdoctoral Researcher Department of Political Science & Graduate Institute of Public Affairs, National Taiwan University, Taiwan.  (PI: Helen K. Liu)
2020 — 2021	Postdoctoral Researcher Department of Environmental Science and Policy, <i>University of California, Davis, USA</i> . (PI: Mark Lubell)
	Education
2015 — 2020	<b>Ph.D. in Public Administration</b> , <i>Florida State University, Tallahassee, USA</i> Dissertation: Executive Turnover, Policy Change, and Evolution of Inter-local Collaboration Network
2012 — 2015	<b>M.A. in Public Administration</b> , <i>National Taiwan University, Taiwan</i> .  Thesis: A Study on Knowledge Transfer among Liaison Officers: The Case of Taiwan Municipal Governments
2007 — 2011	B.A. in Political Science, National Taiwan University, Taiwan.
	Methodological Training
2020	Summer Institutes in Computational Social Sciences (SICSS), Rutgers University, New Brunswick, USA •Digital tracing data collection •Text analysis & machine learning • Experiments
2018	Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA  •Longitudinal Analysis •Bayesian Modeling II •Spatial Econometric
2017	Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA  •Network Analysis II •Causal Inference
2013	Institute for Political Methodology (IPM), Academic Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan
	Publications
	Journal Articles

- 2022 Huang, Chien-shih & Mark Lubell. "Household flood risk response in San Francisco Bay: Linking risk information, perception, and behavior". Regional Environmental Change.
- 2021 Huang, Chien-shih & Frances Berry. "Intergovernmental influence, managerial turnover and city energy policy adoption". Publius: The Journal of Federalism (Forthcoming).

- Huang, Chien-shih & Ruowen Shen. "Does city or state make a difference? The effects of policy framing on public attitudes toward a solar energy program". Journal of Behavioral Public Administration, 3(2).

  2020 Best article honourable mention
- Hung, Mei-jen & Chien-shih Huang. <u>"A content analysis of newspaper headlines about civil servants in Taiwan"</u>. *Taiwan Democracy Quarterly*, 13(3): 45-92.
- Lee, Feng-yu & Chien-shih Huang. "Presidents as party chairmen and the passage of government bills: An analysis of Chen Shui-bian's presidency". *Taiwan Journal of Political Science*, 64: 85-136.

#### Book Review

- Huang, Chien-shih. "Book review: Collaborative innovation in the public sector". *Journal of Public Administration*, 58: 149-56.
- Huang, Chien-shih. "Book review: Working with culture: How the job gets done in public programs". Political Science Quarterly Book Review, 44: 22-25.

#### **Manuscripts Under Review**

†Leading author; R&R=Review and Resubmitted; UR= Under Reviewed

R&R "Partisan evaluation: Examining how partisan media and political elites affect the credibility of government performance" †(with Mei-jen Hung, Mao Wang) at *The Social Science Journal*.

"Executive turnover and policy change in municipal sustainable development".

#### **Working Papers**

†Leading author; CG= Collaborative Governance; EP= Environmental Policy; OB=Organizational Behavior; PP= Policy Process; SNA=Social Network Analysis; BPA= Behavioral Public Administration

- EP+SNA "Geographic scale and the structure of climate adaptation networks in San Francisco Bay, California" †(with Mark Lubell, Francesca Vantaggiato)
- OB+CG "Turnover, interlocal collaboration and organizational performance" †(with Yixin Liu)
- OB+PP "Turnover events, policy conflict, and interlocal service delivery"
- "Evolution of scientific collaboration: A case of interdisciplinary network among researchers"
  - "Co-sponsorship network across policy typology: A preliminary study of Taiwan Legislative Yuan (2000-2015)"

#### **Conference Presentations**

- Huang, Chien-shih, Mark Lubell & Francesca Vantaggiato. "Geographic scale and the structure of climate adaptation networks in San Francisco Bay, California". *the Annual Conference of Association for Public Policy Analysis and Management (APPAM)*, Austin, TX: March 27-29.
- Huang, Chien-shih, Mark Lubell & Francesca Vantaggiato. "Geographic scale and the structure of climate adaptation networks in San Francisco Bay, California". *the 14th Annual Political Networks Conference and Workshops (PolNet)*, Virtual Meeting: June. 14-July 23.
- Huang, Chien-shih & Yixin Liu. "Turnover, interlocal collaboration and organizational performance". *the Annual Conference of Association for Public Policy Analysis and Management (APPAM)*, Virtual Meeting: Nov. 11-13.

**Huang, Chien-shih**, Mei-jen Hung & Mao Wang. "Why don't you believe it? The credibility of information on government performance". *the 2020 Public Management Research Conference (PMRC)*, Manoa, Hawaii: Accepted but canceled.

**Huang, Chien-shih.** "Executive turnover, termination and expansion of municipal sustainable development". *the Annual Conference of Midwest Political Science Association (MPSA)*, Virtual Meeting: Accepted but canceled.

Shrestha, Manoj, **Chien-shih Huang** & Richard Feiock. "Local governance networks: A review of current scholarship and an agenda for the future". *the 2019 Public Management Research Conference (PMRC)*, Chapel Hill, NC: June 11-14.

**Huang, Chien-shih** & Richard Feiock. "Evolution of scientific collaboration: A case of interdisciplinary network among researchers". *the 12th Annual Political Networks Conference and Workshops (PolNet)*, Chapel Hill, NC: May 29-June 1.

**Huang, Chien-shih**, Ruowen Shen, Lingyi Zhou & Richard Feiock. "Does city or state matter? The effects of policy framing on public attitude toward solar PV installation program". *Annual Conference of Midwest Political Science Association (MPSA)*, Chicago, IL: April 4-7.

2018 Choi, Donwe & Chien-shih Huang. "Does collaboration among legislators in cosponsoring bills enhance legislative effectiveness". *the 11th Annual Political Networks Conference and Workshops (PolNet)*, Arlington, Virginia: June 6-9.

**Huang, Chien-shih**. "Understanding the adoption of climate change mitigation policy by US cities: The effect of career and social incentive" . *the 2018 Public Management Research Conference (PMRC)*, Singapore: May 31-June 2.

**Huang, Chien-shih** & Richard Feiock. "Political conflict, administrative turnover, and interlocal service delivery networks". *Annual Conference of Midwest Political Science Association (MPSA)*, Chicago, IL: April 5-8.

- Huang, Chien-shih & Richard Feiock. "City managers' career incentives and local sustainability networks".

  Annual Conference of Midwest Political Science Association (MPSA), Chicago, IL: April 6-9.
- Huang, Chien-shih. "Patterns of co-sponsorship across policy typology: A preliminary study of Legislative Yuan (2000-2015) in Taiwan". *Annual Conference of American Political Science Association (APSA)*, Philadelphia, PA: Sep.1-4.

#### **Invited Talks**

2018

- Geographic scale and the structure of climate adaptation networks in San Francisco Bay, California. Stockholm University, Stockholm Resilience Centre.
- 2020 Leadership turnover and Organizational outcomes: The case of energy policy and police services. National Taiwan University, College of Social Sciences, Local Governance Research Group.

Household flood risk response in San Francisco Bay: Linking risk information, perception, and behavior. *APPAM Communities section, Chinese Policy Scholars Group (CPSG)*.

#### Fellowship, Awards & Honours

- 2021 Winner of Annual Honorable Mention Article Award, Journal of Behavioral Public Administration
- 2020 **Reubin O'D Askew Eminent Scholarship**, Askew School of Public Administration and Policy, Florida State University.

MPSA Conference Fee Waiver Scholarship, Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago, IL.

Winner of Outstanding Research Poster, 2019 Sustainable Health Cities Research Retreat, National Science Foundation (#1444745).

PolNet Conference Fellowship, PolNet Conference, National Science Foundation (#1558713).

**Jerry Collins Experimental Social Sciences Award**, Local Governance Research Lab, Florida State University.

Saundra K. Schneider Scholarship, ICPSR Summer Program, University of Michigan.

**PolNet Conference Fellowship**, *PolNet Conference*, *National Science Foundation* (#1558713).

**Jerry Collins Eminent Scholarship**, Askew School of Public Administration and Policy, Florida State University.

- Taoist Tai Chi Society of the United States of America Scholarship, Taoist Tai Chi Society, Tallahassee, FL.
- 2015 2019 Scholarship of Government Sponsorship for Overseas Study, Ministry of Education, Taiwan.
- 2011 **Research Creativity Award**, National Science Council, Taipei, Taiwan.
- 2010 2011 Undergraduate Student Research Training Fellowship, National Science Council, Taipei, Taiwan.

Last updated: Feb. 2022

### **Teaching Experiences**

2019 — 2020 Research mentor, Center for Undergraduate Research and Academic Engagement, Florida State University

Guide 2 undergraduate students to collect archival local data, including budget & interlocal agreements

2019 — 2020 Instructor, Public Administration in American Society (PAD3003), Florida State University 20-30 undergraduate students. Developed and Taught key conceptions and implications of public administration studies in USA.

2018 — 2019 **Teaching assistant, Public Administration in American Society (PAD3003)**, *Florida State University* 100-120 undergraduate students. Grading homeworks and consulting with students online

#### **Professional Services**

2021 Conference program committee: Annual Political Network Conference (PolNet)

**Journal reviewer**: Publius: The Journal of Federalism; The Ecology and Society; Journal of Urban Affair; Regional Studies

#### **Personal Skills**

**Programming, data analysis and visualisation** in R (tidyverse), STATA, Mplus, SAS, and ArcGIS **Reproducible research** with R Markdown + LaTeX + HTML

Language English (fluent), Mandarin (native), Taiwanese (native)

#### References

Upon request